<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Duke ShinyEd</title>
    <link>/</link>
      <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Duke ShinyEd</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Duke ShinyEd</title>
      <link>/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Variance</title>
      <link>/project/anova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/anova/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this app you will be able to explore Analysis of Variance (ANOVA). ANOVA is a method used in statistical analysis to question whether there is a meaningful difference between groups being studied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-goals&#34;&gt;Learning Goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examine how violations of the assumptions of ANOVA affect the ANOVA test output&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand the relationship between the F-statistic and the ANOVA test output&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Predict how manipulation of between and within group variances will affect the F-statistic and the ANOVA test output&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This app was originally developed by Samantha Owusu-Antwi in Summer 2020 and further updated by Shari Tian in Spring 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis Testing</title>
      <link>/project/hypothesis-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/hypothesis-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often in research and data analysis, we want to investigate certain new claims that challenge what is currently believed, so we take some sample data and see whether or not it supports our new claim. Hypothesis testing is a reliable way to take sample data and test how strongly its evidence supports our new claim &amp;ndash; if the evidence is strong, we can reject the old beliefs and support the new; if it is weak, we cannot reject the old beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This app will allow you to explore hypothesis testing from beginning to end, giving you skills to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify appropriate null and alternative hypotheses for a problem scenario, and effectively interpret test conclusions in terms of the hypotheses/practical scenario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Properly calculate and interpret test statistic, p-value, and alpha level, and understand how to use them to make a conclusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correctly define and interpret Type I and Type II errors, and calculate their probabilities, given various parameters such as alpha, sample size, and testing power. Understand the conditions/assumptions under which each type of error may occur.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app is optimally viewed in full screen on the Google Chrome browser. For the best experience with the Hypothesis Testing App, try following these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-overview&#34;&gt;Step 1: Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the Overview page for a big-picture look at hypothesis testing, as well as the introduction of our running example and other small tips about the app&amp;rsquo;s functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-nullalternative-hypotheses&#34;&gt;Step 2: Null/Alternative Hypotheses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head to the Null/Alternative Hypotheses page to see the interactive sidebar and choose your parameters for your hypothesis test. Then, read about how the hypotheses are formed, and view the distributions graphically!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-test-statisticp-value&#34;&gt;Step 3: Test Statistic/P-Value&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, visit the Test Statistic/P-Value page to explore how to calculate the hypothesis test results, compare values to make a conclusion, and observe your results on a plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-4-type-itype-ii-error&#34;&gt;Step 4: Type I/Type II Error&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, you can look at the Type I/Type II Error tab for an explanation of the kinds of errors that can occur in hypothesis tests and how to reduce them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-5-quiz&#34;&gt;Step 5: Quiz&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, take a quiz on the Quiz tab to test your knowledge and see if you&amp;rsquo;re a hypothesis test expert!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;optional-step-6-resources&#34;&gt;Optional Step 6: Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in further information, like testing parameters other than the population mean or a t-distribution calculator, check out the Resources page for more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can reset parameters, re-sample the data, and re-run the hypothesis test simulation at any time, so be sure to try out different scenarios to see what happens!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This app was developed by Abbey List as part of the Summer 2020 Duke Shiny Ed program.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logistic Regression</title>
      <link>/project/logistic-roc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/logistic-roc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In regression analysis, logistic regression is an important statistical model that can help model/predict binary dependent variables. An important step in creating logistic regression models is choosing the appropriate threshold, which is done through the ROC Curve. In this app you will explore the ROC curve, decision-making thresholds, and corresponding confusion matrices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-goals&#34;&gt;Learning Goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand the logistic regression equation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examine the ROC curve and how it can be used to determine a decision-making threshold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obtain the confusion matrix for a given decision-making threshold, and use the matrix to calculate sensitivity, specificity, and error rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This app was originally developed by Joe Choo in Summer 2020 and further updated by Emmanuel Mokel in Spring 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model Diagnostics</title>
      <link>/project/regression-outliers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/regression-outliers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explore diagnostics for linear regression and use them to understand how influential points can impact the model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-goals&#34;&gt;Learning Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand model diagnostics for linear regression and use them to identify potential influential points&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explore how outliers and influential points can impact the regression model&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examine strategies to address outliers and influential points&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This app was originally developed by Glen Morgenstern in Summer 2020 and further updated by Sean Li in Spring 2021.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
