<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>intro | Academic</title>
    <link>/tag/intro/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>intro</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>intro</title>
      <link>/tag/intro/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis Testing</title>
      <link>/project/hypothesis-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/hypothesis-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often in research and data analysis, we want to investigate certain new claims that challenge what is currently believed, so we take some sample data and see whether or not it supports our new claim. Hypothesis testing is a reliable way to take sample data and test how strongly its evidence supports our new claim &amp;ndash; if the evidence is strong, we can reject the old beliefs and support the new; if it is weak, we cannot reject the old beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This app will allow you to explore hypothesis testing from beginning to end, giving you skills to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify appropriate null and alternative hypotheses for a problem scenario, and effectively interpret test conclusions in terms of the hypotheses/practical scenario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Properly calculate and interpret test statistic, p-value, and alpha level, and understand how to use them to make a conclusion. Understand how sample size can affect test statistic and p-value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correctly define and interpret Type I and Type II errors, and calculate their probabilities, given various parameters such as alpha, sample size, and testing power. Understand the conditions/assumptions under which each type of error may occur.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the best experience with the Hypothesis Testing App, try following these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out the Overview page for a big-picture look at hypothesis testing, as well as the introduction of our running example and other small tips about the app&amp;rsquo;s functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Head to the Null/Alternative Hypotheses page to see the interactive sidebar and choose your parameters for your hypothesis test. Then, read about how the hypotheses are formed, and view the distributions graphically!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, visit the Test Statistic/P-Value page to explore how to calculate the hypothesis test results, compare values to make a conclusion, and observe your results on a plot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then, you can look at the Type I/Type II Error tab for an explanation of the kinds of errors that can occur in hypothesis tests and how to reduce them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, take a quiz on the Quiz tab to test your knowledge and see if you&amp;rsquo;re a hypothesis test expert! Visit the Resources tab for some further reading if you&amp;rsquo;re interested.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can reset parameters and re-run the hypothesis simulation at any time, so be sure to try out different scenarios to see what happens!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;created-by-abbey-list-for-the-shinyed-project-at-duke-university-summer-2020-hosted-by-the-duke-university-statistical-science-department&#34;&gt;Created by Abbey List for the ShinyEd project at Duke University, Summer 2020. Hosted by the Duke University Statistical Science Department.&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
